Hey guys, welcome to the session of credential dunking.
In first point, I have pulled all the necessary files in the for our course in my GitHub
repo.
So you can find it from here and so let's talk about the LSS.
So many of them know what is an LSS and somebody don't know what's what's about the process
came.
So let me open my task manager.
So if you are running the Windows machine, definitely you have a process called LSS, local
security authority process.
Okay, so what the process is about why this process is most sense to process for EDR
as well as the antivirus programs.
So let me do one thing.
Let me try to dump LSS here.
So suddenly my bit different random error software, it's clearly to the process, terminal
entered the process and it's closed my task manager, right?
Yeah, anyway, so we know the LSS is one of the sensitive process.
So we try to do something in LSS, so definitely we'll be get, you know, detector.
Okay, so I was unable to open task manager because my A, we take a control for that process.
Okay.
So let me open this in a VM machine, let me quickly go to the task manager.
So let me explain what is an LSS was, okay, so when you open the machine and when you put
the username and passwords, when you're booting up the machine.
So this both of the credentials, excuse the name and passwords was taken by the LSS process,
okay.
Basically the LSS will be taking your username and passwords and it will be verifying your
credentials into the registry database, so whether the credentials is right or wrong, okay.
So let me go for more time, so when you, when you log in to the machine, when you put
your credentials, username and password, your Windows operating system and the LSS process,
LSS process will be taking your username and password and it will be verifying, verifying
from the certain credential, credential or registries and it will be verifying whether this
username and passwords was correct or not, okay.
Basically that was a functionality of an LSS process, it will be taking your username and
password and it will be verifying that whether the username and passwords is right or wrong,
okay.
So from that we can understand one thing, they LSS contain, so the LSS process contain,
so the LSS process contain our credentials, right, because it will be taking our credentials
when we try to log in, so the LSS contain our credentials, okay.
When you try to dump this LSS, this LSS, we know it contains the credentials, okay.
This process will be holding our credentials, when you try to dump an LSS, this LSS contain
all the username and passwords, so what are the things or what are the users, what are
the passwords and each and everything, which will be holding my LSS, okay.
So if you dump LSS, you can easily get Windows credentials, so whatever credentials you
have, okay.
So because of that, it's one of the most sensitive process coming up into the Windows mission,
so because this process holding all the credentials, okay, like username and passwords, DPA
keys, many, many, many more, okay.
So because of this kind of sensitivity, the antivirus software and the EDR programs, it will
be continuously monitoring the LSS process, if any of them access, if any of the remote
process access to this LSS, it will be creating and it will be terminating that and it
will be creating an alert, so we understand when I try to dump the LSS, so suddenly my
bit differenter, Terminator this task manager right, so I was unable to open task manager
for a few minutes, so because of the sensitivity, my antivirus software and the EDR platform
will be monitoring this LSS, whether any of the process access to the LSS, you will be
automatically getting an alert on the EDRs and antivirus software as well as it will be
terminating the remote process which access to the LSS, okay.
So we will be dumping LSS using various techniques in this topic, like we are not only focusing
on the LSS, we will be focusing on the SAM and system hives in the registries, okay.
So that also has a clamshells like an LSS, so we will be learning different kind of LSS
term that will be used for you followed by your threat actors when coming up to an incident
or an attack, so we will see that in upcoming videos, see you guys, bye bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]